Guide to the Town and Gown Reference Collection, 1894-ongoing UA.01.11.0057
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Town and Gown Reference collection
1894-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0057
1 Linear Feet
The Town and Gown Reference Collection contains files of clippings, reports, publications, flyers, and other material concerning the University's relations with the city and county of Durham and the Research Triangle region. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
900 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Town and Gown Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The collection contains files of clippings, reports, publications, flyers, and other material concerning the University's relationships with, impact on, and service to the city and county, and the region. The bulk dates are 1965 to 1995. Major topics include education, financial matters (including taxation), transportation, and student service to the community through organizations such as Kazi Ya Sanna (work of art in Swahili, 1997) and CHANCE (Concern and Help for the Advancement of Needy Children through Education, 1987). Major programs covered include the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership and the Education Improvement Program, a project funded by the Ford Foundation to assist Durham schools. Durham neighborhoods figuring prominently in the material include Edgemont, Walltown, and Trinity Park. Notable items include an 1894 statement titled Relations of College and Community; The Third Side of the Triangle: Duke University's Interaction with the Community and Region, a 1969 report about the University's public services; and campus publications such as The Duke Community Reporter.
Related Material
Service Duke Community Reporter [serial], circa 1993-1994
Duke University Archives
Durham & Duke [serial]: Duke University economic impact report
Duke University Archives
Community Service Center Records, 1990-2002
Duke University Archives
Durham (N.C.) -- History -- 19th century; Durham (N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- History -- 19th century; Duke University. University Archives
- Subject Files
  - Indexes: to articles in the Trinity/Duke Alumni Register and to archival record groups (Box 1)
  - Affordable housing loan program, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - Africa News Service, 1985-1996 (Box 1)
  - Bull on Bull [a guide to Durham], 1982, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Duke-Durham campaign, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Duke-Durham Fellows Seminar, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership, 1996- (Box 1)
  - Duke and Durham Town-Gown Relationship / William E. King, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Duke outreach, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Duke University Associates Program, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Duke University financial impact, 1997- (Box 1)
  - Durham centennial - Duke Hospitality Day, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Durham County Public Library (Box 1)
  - Durham Education Improvement Program: 4th Annual Report, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Durham Education Improvement Program: Publications, [1965-1970] (Box 1)
  - Durham Education Improvement Program: Reports, [1965-1970] (Box 1)
  - Durham Savoyards (Box 1)
  - East-West Expressway [Durham Freeway], 1979-1983 (Box 1)
  - Edgemont Community Center (Box 1)
  - Hassle House crisis center, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital (Box 1)
  - National Humanities Center, Research Triangle Park (Box 1)
  - Students (Box 1)
  - The Third Side of the Triangle: Duke University's Interaction with the Community and Region, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Triangle Transit Authority (Box 1)
  - Trinity Park (Box 1)
  - United Fund, 1953-1979 (Box 1)
  - Walltown, 1993- (Box 1)
- Chronological Files
  - 1894-1919 (Box 2)
  - 1920-1929 (Box 2)
  - 1930-1939 (Box 2)
  - 1940-1949 (Box 2)
  - 1950-1959 (Box 2)
  - 1960-1969 (Box 2)
  - 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - 1977 (Box 2)
  - 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1979 (Box 2)
  - 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1981 (Box 2)
  - 1982 (Box 2)
  - 1983 (Box 2)
  - 1984 (Box 2)
  - 1985 (Box 2)
  - 1986 (Box 2)
  - 1987 (Box 2)
  - 1988 (Box 2)
  - 1989 (Box 2)
  - 1990 (Box 2)
  - 1991 (Box 2)
  - 1992 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1993 (Box 2)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 2)
  - 2000- (Box 2)